Guide to the BUST Magazine Records, 1993-2015 RL.00180
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
BUST Magazine records
1993-2015
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Bust (Magazine: New York, N.Y.)
RL.00180
43.2 Linear Feet
Debbie Stoller and Marcelle Karp began producing BUST, a third-wave feminist women's magazine, in New York, N.Y., in 1993 as a photocopied zine. Collection documents the behind-the-scenes work required to put together BUST. Materials include issues 1-15 and 20-86 of the magazine; layouts and copy-editing material; biographies of contributors; article submissions; column material (Girls, Fashions, The Shit, etc.); advertisement documentation; correspondence (letter and electronic mail); press coverage of BUST; promotional material; material related to the publication and promotion of the book The BUST Guide to the New Girl Order; and a variety of graphic items. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
29625 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The BUST Magazine records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2001-2015.
Historical Note
Debbie Stoller and Marcelle Karp began producing BUST, a third-wave feminist women's magazine, in New York, N.Y., in 1993 as a photocopied zine. Today, according to the magazine's website (www.bust.com), BUST offers an uncensored view on the female experience.... BUST tells the truth about women's lives and presents a female perspective on pop culture.
Collection Overview
Accession (2001-0009) (1500 items; 2.0 lin. ft.; dated 1993-1998) documents the behind-the-scenes work required to put together BUST. Materials include issues 1-15 of the magazine; layouts and copy-editing material; biographies of contributors; article submissions; column material (Girls, Fashions, The Shit, etc.); advertisement documentation; correspondence (letter and electronic mail); press coverage of BUST; promotional material; material related to the publication and promotion of the book The BUST Guide to the New Girl Order; and a variety of graphic items, including color (9) and black-and-white photographs (6), original black-and-white ink drawings, and color prints (23), as well as color slides (12).
Accession (2009-0082) (24 items; 13.5 lin. ft.; dated 2002-2007) consists of production binders for issues 20-43 of BUST magazine, published from summer 2002 through spring 2007. Each binder contains a copy of the published issue, as well as tabbed sections for each portion of the issue, including features, columns, regulars, sex files, and guides.
Accession (2010-0101) (7875 items; 10.5 lin. ft.; dated 1993-2006) includes production binders, files from the creative director, and files from the Art Department.
Accession (2013-0184) (10125 items; 13.5 lin. ft.; dated 2008-2011) consists of production binders for issues 44-71, published from 2008-2011.
Accession (2015-0040) (1400 items; 3 lin. ft.; dated 2010-2013) consists of production files for issues 64-73, production binders for issues 72-86, and 13 Syquest discs from issues 4-9.
Accession (2015-0097) (1700 items, 4 lin. ft.; dated 1997-2012) consists of production files for issues 10-50, Creative Director Laurie Henzel's notebooks, and graphic materials including original art, color and black and white photographs and color layouts.
Color prints (photographs); Slides (photographs); Drawings (visual works); Periodicals -- Publishing -- United States; Feminism -- United States; Layouts (printer matter); Fan magazines; Women's periodicals, American; Color photographs; Black-and-white photographs; Underground press publishing -- United States; Stoller, Debbie; Karp, Marcelle; BUST Magazine
- Accession (2001-0009), 1993-2000, 4 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  The accession (2001-0009) documents the behind-the-scenes work required to put together BUST. Materials include issues 1-15 of the magazine; layouts and copy-editing material; biographies of contributors; article submissions; column material (Girls, Fashions, The Shit, etc.); advertisement documentation; correspondence (letter and electronic mail); press coverage of BUST; promotional material; material related to the publication and promotion of the book The BUST Guide to the New Girl Order; and a variety of graphic items, including color (9) and black-and-white photographs (6), original black-and-white ink drawings, and color prints (23), as well as color slides (12).
  - BUST, issues 1-15 (Box 1A)
  - Folders for issue 1 (Box 1A)
  - Folders for issues 2-10 (Box 1B)
  - Folders for issues 10-13 (Box 2)
  - Press for BUST Magazine (Box 2)
  - Submissions, issues 4-6 (Box 2)
  - Submissions, issue 7 (Box 3)
  - Random submissions (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1993-1996 (Box 3)
  - BUST book materials
    - Outline (Box 3)
    - Chapters
      - Girls (Box 3)
      - Fashion (Box 3)
      - Media (Box 3)
      - Sex (Box 3)
    - Permissions/biographies (Box 3)
    - Tour (Box 3)
    - Press (Box 3)
    - Party (Box 3)
  - Website (Box 3)
  - Fashion (advertisers) (Box 4)
  - Advertisement sales (Box 4)
- Accession (2009-0082), 2002-2007, 9 boxes
  The addition (2009-0082) (24 items; 13.5 lin. ft.; dated 2002-2007) consists of production binders for issues 20-43 of BUST magazine, published from summer 2002 through spring 2007. Each binder contains a copy of the published issue, as well as tabbed sections for each portion of the issue, including features, columns, regulars, sex files, and guides.
  - Issue 20: Motherhood issue (Cynthia Nixon), Summer 2002 (Box 5)
  - Issue 21: Sex issue (Beck), Summer 2002 (Box 5)
  - Issue 22: Music issue (Le Tigre), Winter 2002 (Box 6)
  - Issue 23: Age issue (Frances McDormand), Spring 2003 (Box 6)
  - Issue 24: Fag Hags (10th anniversary issue), Summer 2003 (Box 6)
  - Issue 25: The Dark Issue (Juliette Lewis), Fall 2003 (Box 7)
  - Issue 26: Independent Spirit (Kelly Osbourne), Winter 2003 (Box 7)
  - Issue 27: Tina Fey, Spring 2004 (Box 7)
  - Issue 28: Jena Malone, Summer 2004 (Box 8)
  - Issue 29: PJ Harvey, Fall 2004 (Box 8)
  - Issue 30: Rosie Perez, December/January 2005 (Box 9)
  - Issue 31: Bjork, February/March 2005 (Box 9)
  - Issue 32: Amy Sedaris, April/May 2005 (Box 10)
  - Issue 33: Sandra Oh, June/July 2005 (Box 10)
  - Issue 34: Justin Theroux, August/September 2005 (Box 10)
  - Issue 35: Susan Sarandon, October/November 2005 (Box 11)
  - Issue 36: Rose McGowan, December/January 2006 (Box 11)
  - Issue 37: Peaches, February/March 2006 (Box 11)
  - Issue 38: Bettie Page, April/May 2006 (Box 12)
  - Issue 39: Yeah Yeah Yeahs, June/July 2006 (Box 12)
  - Issue 40: Tara Subkoff, August/September 2006 (Box 12)
  - Issue 41: Amy Poehler, October/November 2006 (Box 13)
  - Issue 42: Parker Posey, October/November 2006 (Box 13)
  - Issue 43: Gwen Stefani, February/March 2007 (Box 13)
- Accession (2010-0101), 1993-2006 and undated, 7 boxes
  Materials include production binders for issues 2-10, dating from 1993-1997, as well as a binder for the BUST on MTV program, dating from 1996-1997. The rest of the materials are from BUST's creative director and the magazine's Art Department. These include files from issues 7-14; transparencies from printing issues 10-12; original prints, contact sheets, chromes, and negatives of fashion shoots, headshots, celebrities, and other images from the magazine; and original artwork from various artists. Most of the photographs and prints are undated, unsorted, and unattributed, and many include post-its from the Art Department with comments.
  - Issue Binders (Box 14)
    - Issue 2 (Box 14)
    - Issue 3 (Box 14)
    - Issue 4, Sex (Box 14)
    - Issue 5 (Box 14)
    - Issue 6, Men (Box 14)
    - Issue 7, Bad Girls (Box 14)
    - Issue 8, Motherhood (2 folders) (Box 14)
    - BUST on MTV (Box 14)
    - Issue 9 (Box 15)
    - Issue 10 (3 folders) (Box 15)
  - Creative Director Laurie Henzel's art files
    - Veronica Cross portfolio (Box 15)
    - Issue 7 (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Issue 8 (Box 15)
    - Issue 9 (Box 15)
    - Issue 10 (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Issue 11 (Box 15)
    - Issue 11 or 12 (Box 15)
    - Issue 13 (Box 15)
    - Issue 14 (Box 15)
    - Lynn's drawings, undated (Box 15)
    - Henzel's notebooks, with ideas, plans, some interviews, and other creative output (8 books) (Box 15)
    - Graphics and font mockups for BUST (Box 15)
    - Original artwork: Ayun Halliday and Jennifer Ray (Box 15)
  - Photography
    - Vincent Dillo and Jacqueline de Milia (Box 15)
    - Meghan Petersen negatives, 2006-2007 (Box 15)
    - Chris Jerene fashion photographs and negatives (Box 15)
    - Oversize Chris Jerene fashion contact sheets (Oversize-folder 2)
    - Emily Shur, contact sheets (Box 16)
    - Angela Boatwright, contact sheets (Box 16)
    - Bunny Yeager, prints and negatives (Box 16)
    - James Westman, chromes (Box 16)
    - Ken Nicoll, prints and negatives (Box 16)
    - Heidi Hartwig, prints and negatives (Box 16)
    - Sleeved prints (unattributed and undated), with post-its and comments (Box 17)
    - Original prints and contact sheets (unattributed and undated) (Box 18)
  - Transparencies (Box 19)
    - Issue 10, Sex (3 folders) (Box 19)
    - Issue 11, Girlfriends (2 of 4 folders) (Box 19)
    - Issue 11, Girlfriends (2 of 4 folders) (Box 20)
    - Issue 12 (4 folders) (Box 20)
- Accession (2013-0184), 2008-2011, 9 boxes
  This addition consists of production binders from issues 44-71, published from 2008-2011.
  - Issues 44-46 (Box 21)
  - Issues 47-49 (Box 22)
  - Issues 50-53 (Box 23)
  - Issues 54-56 (Box 24)
  - Issues 57-59 (Box 25)
  - Issues 60-62 (Box 26)
  - Issues 63-65 (Box 27)
  - Issues 66-68 (Box 28)
  - Issues 69-71 (Box 29)
- Accession (2015-0040), 1997-2013, 3 boxes
  - Bust on MTV, 1997 (Box 30)
  - Production files from issues 64-73 (Box 30)
  - Production binders for issues 72-77 (Box 30)
  - Production binders for issues 78-84 (Box 31)
  - Production binders for issues 85-86 (Box 32)
  - 13 Syquest discs for issues 4-9 (Box 33-34)
- Accession (2015-0097), 1998-2015, 5 boxes
  - Interns, 2001 (Box 35)
  - Content plan, 2001 (Box 35)
  - Distribution, 2001 (Box 35)
  - Partnership agreement, undated (Box 35)
  - Contributors, issue 10 (3 folders) (Box 35)
  - Production files and binders, issues 11-19 (Box 35)
  - Production files, issues 20-50 (Box 36)
  - Creative director Laurie Henzel's 10 notebooks, 2002-2012 (Box 36)
  - 9 Liv Tyler photographs, color and black and white prints (11" x 14") (Box 37)
  - Esther Pearl Watson color print, "Tammy Pierce is Unloveable", number 100/100 (12" x 17") (Box 37)
  - Cover and layout proofs, 2010-2015 (Box 37)